All right, welcome. Thank you for
coming. I'm James Ward. I work at AWS on
Agentic stuff in MCP. And uh
>> I'm Josh Long. I work on the Spring team
as the uh as as the loudest person
>> there. Okay, great. Thank you for doing
that. Um, so we're going to just give
you a real quick 25minut run through of
building AI agents using Java. And you
may not think like, oh, Java, it's a
great place for a AI agents. It actually
is like like that's where your business
logic is. That's where a lot of your
domain logic in a lot of organizations
is defined. So why don't we put the AI
agents where the data and where the
business logic is. So we're going to
real quickly go through that in 25
minutes with Spring AI. Uh, Spring is a
great foundation for building business
applications, all sorts of stuff. Um,
and they have a great AI package that
we're going to use. So, what are we
going to build a? Oh, yeah. And that's
our information. That's our slide.
>> This is information. Hi, welcome. Uh,
you can find us online. We're very
online. We can find us on LinkedIn. Uh,
we are YouTubers. Some things we can
some things we're not proud of, but hey,
we do it. Um, we have to look, the hard
part about this is what are we going to
do as our sample domain? Obviously,
you've probably heard about the Spring
Pet Clinic. This is a sample application
that demonstrates how to use spring in
terms of uh this very simple domain of
like adopting pets and all that or you
know taking care of pets and we thought
and I like the domain. I do I like the
idea of dogs and and cats and and
animals and all that.
>> Who loves pets?
>> Everybody but sometimes these animals
can be a little spicy and uh you know
even they deserve a loving home and this
reminds me of a dog about which we
learned during the pandemic uh named
Prancer. Now Prancer's owner was trying
to rehhouse this dog and she wrote this
ad that went viral. She said, "Okay,
I've tried. I've tried for the last
several months to post this dog for
adoption and make him sound palatable.
The problem is he's just not." And she
continues on. She says, "There's not a
very big market for neurotic,
man-hating, animal-hating, children
hating dogs that look like gremlins."
And she continues on. She says, "I uh I
was excited to see him come out of his
shell and become a real dog. I'm
convinced at this point that he's not a
real dog, but more like a vessel for a
traumatized Victorian child that now
haunts our home." And uh she continues
on and it's really hysterically funny.
You should read the whole thing. Uh but
she signs off warning. Oh, he's only two
years old and will probably live to be
21 through pure spite. So take that into
account if you're interested. So I think
about this this spicy dog all the time,
right? And by the way, super cute. I
would totally pet that dog. I I'd
probably lose a digit, but I would pet
that dog. This dog went viral. Okay, so
here's uh People magazine. Prer the
demonic. Come on. Oh, I hate the
internet today. The internet is the
worst. Okay, Prancer. The demonic
Chihuahua's new owner says he's helped
her heal from past trauma. So cute. Look
at that doggo. Uh, here's USA Today.
Demonic Chihuahua Hellscape. Meet
Prancer, the puppy everyone wants after
a brutally honest Facebook review. And
here's Buzzfeed, right? We caught up
with Prancer, the viral nightmare
Chihuahua. Right. And of course, here's
the New York Times local paper. Right.
Oh, hey,
>> server.
>> Cloudflare. What are you doing?
>> Is it that? What happened?
>> Try this again. They just had an unwrap
in there, you know.
>> No, it's my favorite. This is Oh, the
website's down. That's sad. Okay. Well,
anyway, nonetheless, I think about this
terrible, terrible dog all the time. I
want to build a a place where we can
adopt dogs, even terrible, terrible
ones.
>> If AI can do anything, it better help us
adopt pets.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
>> That's where we're going.
>> So, that's what we're going to do. And
and in order to undertake that effort,
we need to like uh we need some models,
AI models. Let's talk about that.
>> Yep. So, we're going to use Bedrock for
this. Bedrock has a lot of different
models available. Uh they're hosted so
you can just use them on demand. 249
different models you can choose from in
the marketplace of models. So there's
the anthropic models, there's the
DeepSeek models. Uh Amazon has their own
models. Lots of different models to
choose from there. So that's what we're
going to use. We've already set up
Josh's laptop to be authenticated to
AWS. So that part we've already done. So
now we can use the AI models uh from
Bedrock. Now, the reason I like bedrock
is because it's you you have one API,
but behind the scenes, you can just
switch out the models. Yeah. And
>> just a config parameter, which we'll see
in a minute.
>> So, all the Java code we're going to
write would be the same no matter what
which of these models we use in the back
end. Okay. So, I think I'm happy with
that. Let's go ahead now and build a
project. Uh, obviously, we're going to
do that here at my second favorite place
on the internet. My first favorite place
is is and has always been production. I
love production. You should love
production. You should go as early and
often as possible. Bring the kids. Bring
the family. The weather's amazing. It's
the happiest place on earth. It is
better than Disneyland. But if you've
never been to production, begin your
journey here at start.spring.io. And
what we're going to do is we have to
build a new service. Let's call it an
assistant because after all, that's what
we're going to do is we're going to
assist people in adopting dogs, right?
And we have some choices we need to
make. First and foremost of which is
what version of Java do we want to use?
Look, there are three radio boxes here,
but only one valid choice. You see,
Java's 21 and 2017 are from the distant
distant past. Long since deprecated,
creakingly old, way past irrelevant
versions of Java. You should never ever
be using these versions of Java.
Instead, only Java 25. Java 25 brings
one of my all-time double Dutch favorite
features, uh, which is this. So, I'm
going to open up this file here. void
main. Okay. And io.print line. Hi. Okay.
And I'm just going to execute that. I'm
not going to compile it. I'm just going
to run it like an interpreted piece of
code. And so, what I've done is I've
executed this code like a script. And
the script is written in Java. So, you
know what this means? You know what this
is? This is in the first time in
recorded history a good JavaScript.
Now this hasn't happened before, right?
It's been 30 plus years of the bad
JavaScript. Now we have good Java
script. Okay, so much better. So we're
going to use Java 25. We're going to
bring in the web support. We're going to
bring in a database access layer OM kind
of thing. We're going to need a database
by the way. Which database? I would go
for Postgress usually.
>> Yeah, usually we use Postgress, but we
need vector storage which we're going to
get into rag and embedding. We'll talk
about that. Should I use one of these
other vector storage?
>> Lots of options, but we're going to use
PG vector. PG vector is vector storage
in Postgress.
>> Okay, so it's two for one. We're going
to get both a SQL database and a vector
store in one, but logically they're two
separate components. It just happens to
be we have one server doing double duty.
Okay. Uh we're going to bring in
bedrock. Of course, we've got both
choices.
>> Yep. So, we're picking both Amazon
Bedrock and Amazon Bedrock Converse. The
reason for that is that the embeddings
are going to use an embedding model. And
so, we use the the basic one for that.
And then the chat client is going to use
the converse API. So pull in that one.
So two different libraries
>> and actuator for observability. And I
think that's it. Is it
>> uh MCP client?
>> Oh, yep. Thank you, sir. As usual, got
my
>> and then memory
>> chat. Yeah, there you go. Okay.
>> So it's just adding some dependencies to
how we're going to kick off the the
creation of this project. So you've
created the project and now you're going
to use a Java script to open that
project.
>> Darn right.
>> Yep. Let's set up some configuration
here. So,
>> now we need a little bit of
configuration. There's there's some in
here that uh is going to be revealed as
we go. So, we're just going to throw it
all in and then and then we'll explain
it as we go, right?
>> But we do need to set the model that
we're going to use for our chat with the
AI. So, we're going to use the Amazon
Nova light model. Again, that could be
any of those 249 models on Bedrock. Uh
we're going to use another model for the
embeddings. That's the Bedrock coher
model in this case. So, we've configured
that. We've had to match the dimensions
of that model to our PG vector store. So
we set that and then we set some
parameters like yeah initialize the data
uh in the database and virtual threads.
Virtual threads are super cool. It's a
new feature a newish feature in Java
that makes our thread efficiency much
better on the JVM. So we'll use that.
We're going to set up our observability
endpoint which we'll show in a little
bit
>> and connect to our database. All right.
>> So that's our config.
>> So now let's build our adoptions AI.
It's going to be just a simple chatbot
kind of thing, right? So, we're going to
build a little controller here that
answers questions about dogs in the
shelter, right? So, let's do that. We're
going to take a parameter, which is
going to be the uh question, and we'll
also have a path variable, which will be
the user name. And we'll discover what
that is in just a bit. But in order to
do this, we're going to take advantage
of the Spring AI chat client. Okay, chat
client is your one-stop shop for all
things uh working with chat models. In
order to do that, just like anything
else in the Spring ecosystem, you inject
the builder, build it, and you got an
instance of it. I love the chat client.
I believe that this is written by the
absolute best people, right? The the
best people worked on this code.
>> Nice work on that, buddy.
>> Yeah, thank you. We do our best. So,
this is this uh AI.prompt passing in the
question.all.content.
Okay, let's see what that spot us. So
that's our like super basic ability to
receive an HTTP request, take the
question from it, pass it to the LLM,
and return the response. So in a couple
lines of code, we should have a working
chatbot. Doesn't do much yet, but we'll
we'll add on to it as we go.
>> What's your question?
>> Let's just establish brass tax saying
hello.
>> Yeah. Although we are going to talk to a
database. Let me make sure we have no
tables here.
>> Oh yeah, let's check out our database.
Remember, the goal ultimately is to uh
get the dogs
adopted. So, drop uh this table. Here we
go. Goodbye. And we've got a dog table.
And you can see down here we've got our
buddy Prancer. His ID is 45. His name is
Prancer. And he's described as a
demonic, neurotic, man-hating,
animal-hating, children-hating dog that
looks like a gremlin. And surprising to
everyone, no owner. Okay. So,
>> let's ultimately we're going to discover
this dog and be able to adopt him,
right? He's a dog of our dreams or or
nightmare. So, first things first, let's
establish a dial tone. My name is Josh.
All right, we're connected despite the
Wi-Fi. And uh it's says, "Hello, Josh.
It's nice to meet you." It's working.
So, that was the request of the LM. So,
we responded with that when we give it,
"My name is Josh." This should be fine,
right? No pro. Oh, why does this always
happen? They always forget me as soon as
I talk to somebody. It says, "I'm sorry,
but I can't tell your name because I
don't have access to personal
information."
>> That's not great.
>> Well, so the reason is is that the LLM
doesn't have state. And so in order for
it to remember things, we have to
assemble memory that then we wire into
the chat client so that then when we
make calls, we can pass in the memory.
That's essentially just adding more into
the prompt that we're going to send over
to the LLM. So what we can do with
Spring AI is create that chat memory.
We're going to use the actual database
that Postgress database that we saw uh
configured to store those memories.
There's lots of different ways that you
can persist the memories and then
different ways that you can provide the
memory to the actual chat client to the
LLM. We're going to use the what's it
called message window chat memory. So
that's going to just create a rolling
window through so that we don't save
everything forever. We save I think what
is there a default 20 messages or
something like that. 20.
>> Yeah.
>> So okay. So you've configured our chat
memory uh connected to the database.
That was a couple lines of code. You're
flying. Um and then we need to tell our
chat client about that chat memory. The
way that we do that in Spring is with an
advisor. An adviser is essentially an
interceptor so that when a request is
going to go to the LM, we can intercept
the request, augment it in some way,
pass more data or change whatever is
going over to the LLM, and then we can
also intercept the response back out.
And so there's an out of the box advisor
for chat memory. And you already got it
working.
>> Got it working. Easy peasy. All right.
So we're connected. It's got memory.
Life is good. I think we're making good.
>> Do you want to show them the table? The
memory.
>> The table. Oh, yeah. There's a table.
That's one of those properties that we
set up. You saw that here. We said uh
initialize the schema for the chat
memory. It's going to store it durably
in the table here. And we've got the
Spring AI chat memory table. It says,
"Hi, my name is Josh." That's the user.
That's us. And then hello Josh from the
model. Okay, the assistant. And then
what's my name? That's from us. And then
hello Josh, it's nice to meet you from
the assistant. So we have the back and
forth interactions uh in the
>> So that was just the default with that
memory window um way to do that. And we
can customize it, we can use other ones,
whatever we want to do. But that is just
the the simplest way to add memory,
>> right? I think we've got we've got
memory, we've got context now, but still
it's a little bit of a sort of unfocused
thing, isn't it?
>> Oh, wait. Did we configure the memory to
be per user?
>> Oh, yeah. We should do that. No, we
don't. We have no correlation. Yeah,
you're right.
>> Yeah. So right now it's just like global
memory for all users, which probably
isn't what you want. So we can go in on
our actual chat request. That's where we
know what the user is and we can tell it
all right pull the the user ID out which
was passed in as a URL parameter and
then uh use that to find the actual
write memory. And likely you're going to
use security and you're going to pull
out you know some actual ident
identifier of the user and use that. But
right now we just put that into the URL.
>> It's in the URL right here Josh. Yeah
exactly. Okay. So that's worked. Nice.
Okay. So now we it's it's connected. We
have correlation with the identity, but
it's still unfocused. And I think we
need something to give it a mission.
>> Yeah. I mean, we don't want people using
our chatbot to like do their homework
and, you know, write code and that kind
of stuff. We really want it to be
focused on helping people adopt Prancer
and other wonderful pets. So, let's give
it a mission.
>> Right. I happen to have a pre-written
system prompt. That's what we're going
to give it is a a system prompt. I
happen to have one pre-written here. And
we're just going to use that prompt. And
no, wait. I'm so sorry.
You got to you got to dog that file,
man.
>> There we go. Okay, got it. So, now we'll
paste this in here and we'll configure
that
>> here.
>> So, now we just set the system prompt
that's just going to go into the context
when we make the request. So, what is
our system prompt? What are we telling
this thing to do?
>> You are an AI powered assistant to help
people adopt a dog from the adoption
agency named Pooch Palace with locations
in Antworp, Soul, Tokyo, Singapore,
Paris, Mumbai, New Delhi, uh Barcelona,
San Francisco, and London. Did I say
Antworp?
Brooklyn.
>> I meant Brooklyn. Ha.
>> There we are. Oh. Oh. OH. NO OFFENSE.
OH, POOR GUY. The one guy from Ant. I'm
so sorry. Oh, okay. Well, you know what?
>> You could have picked Singapore to
replace.
>> I don't know. We could just add We'll
expand. We're a global dog adoption
conglomerate. Um, okay. So, now we go
here and uh I guess we just ask it like
let's ask it about the dogs, huh?
>> Yeah. Let's find find the dog of our
dreams
>> or nightmares.
Any neurotic dogs?
>> Hi Josh. Currently we don't have any
dogs listed as neurotic. Okay. So it's
it's and it even mentions Pooch Palace,
right? It it knows the it did it did the
assignment. It knows what what's up. But
still it's not able to connect us with
any of the data because it doesn't have
>> any of the data.
>> We got our dogs in the database. How do
we get them into our AI? So what we're
going to do is set up what's called rag.
Rag is a pattern for being able to take
data and inject it into the context that
we're going to send to the LLM. And so,
of course, Springai has support for rag
built into it. There's a few things we
need to set up to do this. So, first we
have to connect to our database. So,
you're going to add in um our Oh, you
got the question answer advisor. We'll
do that in a minute. Um we don't have
our dog database stuff yet. Okay. So,
we're going to use this question answer
advisor. Uh that's going to be another
interceptor that's going to be able to
essentially take the prompt that the
user entered and we're going to do a
similarity search on that prompt with
our dogs. But to do that similarity
search, the best way to do that is by
taking all of our dogs and taking the
prompt and turning them into vectors.
And then we can do an easy cosign
similarity search uh that's built into
PG vector. So we're able to then match
that prompt to the most likely dog. And
then we're going to take that dog and
put it into the prompt and that question
answer adviser kind of does all the hard
work underneath the covers. But we do
need to be able to get our dogs out of
the database. And then we do have to
create the vectors for each of those
dogs. So we are going to do that in kind
of a cheaty way here. Normally you do
that on create and update is when you're
going to vectorize and that's going to
go out to the bedrock cohhere model get
the embeddings get the vectors for our
dogs and then store those into pg
vector. And so Josh is doing that uh
here kind of just manually one off.
We're going to take our dogs get the
vector form. So when we create the
document that's getting a string.
>> So I this is actually a spring AI
document.
>> Oh y
>> but you know I just realized it's for
dogs. So we shall call it a document.
Okay. Of course. Yep. Document. Okay.
So, we're creating our document. And
when we do that vector store add, that's
actually going out to the model, getting
the vectors, and then putting them into
the PG vector database. You want to show
the vector. There we are. There's the
embedding. So, we got the string. Uh, we
have the embeddings. Those are just
essentially an array of numbers to
represent that dog.
>> And vector stores are optimized to
search for that kind of data. I'm I'm
not going to re vectorize all this data
on each restart. So, effectively, I'm
commenting it out. So the next So you
saw that this took a very long time
because we had to vectorize all those
records.
>> That was startup and and the
vectorzation.
>> Yeah. So I'm gonna reload now. Here we
go.
>> Okay. So we've got our vectorized forms
of the dogs. We've got our question
answer adviser and then you added the
adviser in.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. Great. So we've got rag set up.
>> Hey Josh, based on the context
information provided, we do have a dog
named Prancer who's described as
neurotic. So Prer, we found OUR BUDDY.
WE FOUND HIM. AWESOME. THE DOG OF OUR
DREAMS.
>> Let's adopt that guy.
>> Yeah, but this is text. Yeah, if I
wanted to pass this data around to other
layers of the API, the abstraction, I
would want a correlation ID or
something. How do I take actionable data
out of this? Unless I'm passing this
straight to the user, right? So, one
possibility is you could turn this text
into a actual typed object. So, dog
adoption suggestion int ID string name
string description and you know just
just as a possibility you say instead of
content you ask for this entity back.
Right here we are like that. And I go
over here replace that. reload and ask
the same uh question.
>> So in a larger agentic uh larger agentic
system, you're not always going to be
passing string in, string out. A lot of
times you want to pass structured data
in get structured data out and so of
course spring can allow us to get that
structured data out. Uh what's funny is
that the LLM put it into JSON and then
we des serialized it into that record
and then we serialized it back to JSON.
So kind of silly in this case, but but
hey, you know,
>> and I do actually want the string. So in
this case, we'll keep that. But yeah,
>> it's nice to know you can get structured
typed objects back. Okay. Um All right.
So now, yeah, you're right. Let's adopt
it. I think the first thing that we'll
have to do is figure out when we can
swing by the the the shop. So let's
build a tool.
>> Likely we have like a scheduling system
behind this. And what we want to do is
wire our agent to that scheduling
system. So we can use tools to do this.
A common pattern with LLMs is
essentially what you're doing is you are
saying, "Hey LM, here are the things
that you can do outside of yourself."
They're tools. And so we are going to
first define the tool for our scheduling
system. We're just going to hardcode. We
don't have an actual dog scheduling
adoption scheduling system. So we're
just hard coding and saying you can
adopt it in 3 days. And so we're going
to return that from the schedule method.
And so now we're going to be able to
provide that schedule method as a tool
to the agent. And then what the LM's
going to do is say, all right, when the
user says they want to schedule to pick
up Prancer, then we're going to call
that tool. And this is running in
process with the agent. So in this case,
we'll get to MCP in a second, but in
this case, we're actually going to call
in memory to this this uh schedule
method right here. So we annotate it
with that tool. We add a description.
That description is very important. Why
is that important?
>> Well, when remember when you were a kid
and your your mom told you to use your
words, this is what she was trying to
tell you to do is to clearly document
your AI inputs. Okay, so that's what
we're doing here.
>> So we do that so that the OM knows when
it should call that tool. So that that
natural language description very
important also for the parameters. The
LM is going to figure out what
parameters go in what slots. And so the
descriptions again are important there
as well. Okay. Did we got it get it
wired up? Okay. We have we found
Prancer. We've got memory. So now it
should know when who which dog we're
talking about.
>> Yeah.
>> And we're going to ask when can we pick
it up from the Brooklyn location
and if everything works.
>> November 22nd. Today is the 19th.
>> Fantastic. So, we know now that it did
in fact call our tool. So, the way that
that worked underneath the covers is we
made the request to the LLM. We gave it
the list of tools and then the LM said,
"Oh, I need you to actually call that
tool schedule." And so, then on the
Spring agent side, it actually made the
call to the schedule tool with the right
parameters and then fed that information
back to the LLM and then got the
response back from the LM and then
that's what we actually sent back to the
user. Okay. Okay. So, but now maybe you
don't want those tools to be in memory.
Maybe you've got vendors that are
providing MCP servers. Maybe you're
taking any of the thousands of MCP
servers that are out there and you want
to wire those MCP servers in instead.
So, we're going to refactor this
application, pull out the local tool,
turn it into an MCP server, and then
wire that remote MCP server up to our
agent instead of doing the local tool
calling. So, you copied and pasted
everything in
>> refactor to use the new annotations.
>> We're going to set the port to be
different because we don't want a port
conflict. We did change the annotations
there. Uh you can use the same
annotations. It just takes a little more
setup to do it. But at MCP tool, same
description and start. Oh, MCP
inspector. Great tool for being able to
debug the MCP server. So now we can go
look in here. Connect up. Make sure that
>> 8081
>> computers.
>> Yep. So we'll connect to that. There we
go. We're connected. We can list the
tools. We can see that there's a
schedule tool. So great. So our MCP
server verified in the inspector to be
functional. Now we can actually wire it
in back into our agent.
>> So that's the schedule. Let's go back to
the code where we now have a a dog
adoption schedule shaped hole in our
compilation unit. And here we're going
to inject a sync MCP tool callback
provider. Rolls right off the tongue.
Easy name. Okay.
>> This is just going to be able to read
some configuration for the MCP server
servers that we want to connect to and
give us a handle to that. And then we
can set in our our chat client the uh
the hook to that so that then our chat
client knows about those MCP servers.
Okay. Then we need to provide the HTTP
URL to connect to that MCP server. So
that's just a config parameter. And that
looks right to me.
>> Okay. Here we go. Now we're going to try
it again.
>> So remember we have two Java processes
running. We've got scheduleuler on 881.
We've got our assistant on on 8080.
Right? And now if I ask the assistant on
8080 for help, it should invoke this
tool on AD81. Let's just see that that's
true. So, uh, well, first of all, let me
clean the cache so we don't have any.
Sometimes it'll cheat, which is kind of
nice, but we don't want it to cheat. We
don't want to see it in the memory and
be like, I figured this out already. Why
redo the work?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Prer.
And remote MCP call. There we go. Okay.
Pick up Prancer. So then we can verify.
Yep, it sure enough made that MCP call
over to that remote MCP server.
>> All right, so great. So end to end uh
working with MCP, we've got our agent,
we've got our memory, we've got our rag.
Uh what else do we have? System prompts.
>> Yeah, system prompt, user prompts. And
this is the real opportunity here is
remember it was trivial for us to add
all this stuff to an existing Spring
Boot application, right? This is just
code you probably have in your system in
your organization. That's institutional
knowledge that represents years and
years of uh sort of building up. And
it's like the like a the grease in a pot
that you just keep reusing to to enrich
the food and the flavor. That stuff is
there already. Just add the AI
integrations off the side of it. You're
off to the races. You're ready to go.
This is a really good opportunity for
us. And by the way, strongly typed,
right? Nice. All the way through. I'm
not telling Python, hey, this is a thing
I need in this shape. Here's schema. The
Java object tells it. It's already
enough. You know, this is an amazing
opportunity.
>> So, one of the concerns usually is,
okay, great. Uh, these tokens are
actually expensive. We've been able to
get it all working. But how do I get
some insight into my token use?
>> Oh, good point. You definitely want to
keep an eye on that. By the way, we're
using Bedrock. It's like pennies for
what we we haven't I don't think we've
spent a penny so far today in this demo,
right? We haven't spent a penny yet on
that particular service. Uh but you
know, you do want to keep an eye on it.
Um
>> so we're expecting our dog adoption
service to go viral and become a whale
the next whale whatever. So so we got to
be able to observe our token usage. So,
Spring has built-in support for
observability and it uses something
called actuator and micrometer and it's
able to export all the metrics for our
application across everything in our
application. So, one kind of standard
observability uh system and of course
Spring AI integrates into that and so we
can go and look up the uh token
information as an example for for how
many tokens we've used. How many have we
used for this? Uh oh, and this is
probably just the current session, so
not a whole lot. Yeah, but
>> request model. Here's the type. And by
the way, this is in memory right here.
But it's all powered by micrometer,
which is a third party API that we built
that in turn can be used to publish
metrics and distributed tra distributed
traces to any time series database of
your choice, including Amazon's
>> Cloud Cloudatch. Yep.
>> And that's supported here as well.
>> Yeah. So you can take all of the metric
data, publish it externally to your
observability platform.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's observability.
>> Yeah. I think and we've got an
application. We still have two minutes
to spare, I think.
>> Wow. We did it.
>> You nice and fast.
>> Um well, we took some leisurely turns.
We took some time to have some fun with
our friend from uh Belgium here. Uh no,
we this is easy. Even I can do this,
right? If we can do this, then you can
definitely do this. This is an amazing
opportunity. So, when people say they're
doing AI engineering and they get all
hoyy about it, just remind them it's
just REST APIs. It's just integration.
It's the glue code. It's the modern
world glue code, right? This is the kind
of stuff that JavaM Java and JVM
developers have been doing as their
bread and butter for decades. We are
uniquely well positioned here, right?
Take seize this moment, take this
opportunity to build something amazing.
>> Yeah. So, do you want to highlight the
Spring AI 1.1 release and the MCP parts
of that
>> just came out? Uh we just released
Spring AI 1.1 last week. Uh that's what
we used here the entire time. It has
full support for the MCP specification
and we are also working we you know we
we the Spring AI team
last November. Do you remember November?
cuz I I I I don't last November when
they announced when anthropic announced
the MCP specification, we the Spring AI
team were the first to build an
implementation in Java in the weeks that
followed literally the same month and
that got donated eventually. So the
official MCP SDK for Java is is code
that we wrote and then we rebased on. So
it's it's not just the best integration
with the MCP SDK, it is the MCP SDK,
right? It's just a really really good uh
specification
>> and you can use it outside of the world
of Spring. So there's the Java SDK for
MCP that's maintained primarily by the
Spring team and you can use that with
other ecosystems in Java. Uh you can use
it directly or you can use it in Spring
AI which makes it super easy as you saw
today. So
>> well I have a question now. Who learned
something new? All right. Who had fun?
>> Us two. Thank you so much everybody.
>> Thank you.
Bam. Bam.
>> So good.
Heat.